

Damiano Tagliaferri

Via per Netro, 51 13888 Mongrando (BI), Italy +39 3331429615 dam.tagliaferri@gmail.com Portfolio - LinkedIn - GitHub

ABOUT ME

I am a passionate and versatile game developer, with three years of experience crafting immersive single-player, multiplayer and XR experiences for PC and mobile.

I have a very organized, methodical and curious personality, with strong communication skills powered by my diverse skill set that includes game design, 3D modeling, animation, and music production.

SKILLS

- · OOP and functional programming
- 3D math
- · Mobile and XR development
- C#, C++, Python, JS, Lua
- · Game Al programming patterns
- Unity (Online Services, UniTask, DOTween...)
- Dynamic audio implementation (FMOD)
- Version control (Git)
- · Fluent spoken and written italian and english

Extra tools:

Dev: UE5, Godot 4Audio: Ableton Live

· Graphics: Blender, GIMP, Krita, Aseprite

EDUCATION

Software engineering (2018 - On hold)

Politecnico di Torino Turin, Italy

UE5 development course (2022)

Udemy *Online*

Game Design (2021 - 2022)

Self taught

"The Art of Game Design" by Jesse Schell

"Level UP" by Scott Rogers

WORK EXPERIENCE

Unity developer

000 Labs, 2023

- Worked on PoC that helped company raise 300,000\$ investment
- Online multiplayer with tile-based procgen
- Unity integration with Flutter app and server backend

Unity developer

Freelance, 2021-2023

• Mobile and XR development

Guitar and music theory teacher

Freelance, 2017-2020

· Solid communication skills

PERSONAL PROJECTS

"Ice & Fire Project" - vertical slice

Lead developer in a Scrum managed team working on an original hack & slash game for PC.

"SkyGuard AR" - solo personal project

Self-published AR Android game with full Play Games integration and Unity Ads.

GAME JAMS

"Afterimage" - GDtv Jam 2023

Lead developer and Game designer, managing a team of 4 in a ten days jam.

"Undergroove" - GGJ 2023

Lead developer and Lead designer, managing a team of 12 in a ten days jam.

"Neden" - GGJ 2022

Lead developer (Gameplay, AI) and animator in a ten days jam.

More projects are available on my personal <u>portfolio</u>, <u>GitHub</u> and <u>itch.io</u>